COLLINS MWANGA MAKAMU

Nairobi, Kenya | collinsmakamu95@gmail.com | (+254) 705547809 | Linkedin || Github

Flutter Developer || Cybersecurity Analyst

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated Software Developer and a Cybersecurity Junior with a passion for mobile, web development, digital forensics, threat hunting and incident response.2 years of experience building interactive mobile applications and creating responsive websites. Currently building my Cyber Security Analyst skill through the use of various certifications and projects/labs.

EDUCATION

Daystar University Nairobi, Kenya

Bachelor of Science Applied Computer Science

June 2018 – December 2021

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Foundations of Cybersecurity, Udemy Flutter & Dart 2023, Udemy Web Developer 2023.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

HTML, Javascript, React, Tailwindcss, SCSS, Node.js, MongoDB, GoogleSheets, Python, SQL, Git, Linux

WORK EXPERIENCE

Swirlville Limited Nairobi, Kenya

Flutter Developer

Jan 2022 – July 2022

- Collaborated with designers to implement UI/UX designs and convert them into interactive and responsive Flutter interfaces
- Assisted in debugging and fixing bugs to ensure smooth app functionality and a positive user experience.

Ministry Of Lands
IT Intern

Nairobi, Kenya

June 2020 – August 2020

- Assisted in setting up and configuring networking infrastructure, including IP routes and connecting networking
- cables for multiple departments.
 Provided efficient troubleshooting support for various computer issues experienced by staff members.

FnP Fashions Nairobi, Kenya

Web Developer- Contract.

May 2020 – *July* 2020

- Designed and developed a responsive website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, ensuring cross-browser compatibility and optimal performance.
- Utilized Git for version control and collaborated with a team to address issues and improvements.

PROJECTS

Expense Tracker Nairobi, Kenya

- Application that allows users to track their spending habit and be able to see a visual representation of their expenditure.
- Utilized Flutter, Dart and Google sheets as the back-end.

Cyber Security Detection and Monitoring Lab

Nairobi, Kenya

- Designed a virtualized homelab network to test vulnerabilities and practice threat detection
- Utilized Splunk, Kali Linux Security Onion and an Active Directory environment to simulate a small enterprise network.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

GOOGLE Developer Students Club

Nairobi, Kenya

Bachelor of Science Applied Computer Science

August 2020 – July 2021

- Mentored and supported individual team members in their personal projects and technical growth.
- Organized and facilitated regular meetings and workshops for the DSC team to foster collaboration and skill development.

UNITED NATIONS Nairobi, Kenya

Liaison Officer

October 2017 – December 2017

- Collaborated with internal teams to ensure that the organization's projects and activities aligned with UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) and other UN priorities.
- Served as the primary point of contact and communication bridge between the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Kenya and the United Nations in regards to selected dignitaries.